Benjamin Spock and Mary Morgan Papers
Benjamin Spock and Mary Morgan Papers
- Writings
  - Books
    - Baby and Child Care Seventh Edition (1998), with Steven Parker, 4 folders
      - Manuscript, ch. 5-24, 26, 4 folders (Box 431)
      - Ross Labs correspondence and discussion (Box 431)
      - Revisions, 2 folders (Box 431)
      - Revisions, 2 folders (Box 432)
    - Baby and Child Care Eighth Edition (2004), with Robert Needlman
      - Author's copy-edited manuscript, pp. 1-799, 4 folders (Box 432)
      - Author's copy-edited manuscript, pp. 800-1198, 2 folders (Box 433)
      - Draft, 8/7/03, pp. 1-578, 3 folders (Box 433)
      - Edited draft, 12/11/03, pp. 1-900, 6 folders (Box 434)
      - Edited draft, 12/11/03, pp. 901-1199, 3 folders (Box 435)
      - Proofs, pp. 1-692, 4 folders (Box 435)
      - Proofs, pp. 693-936, 2 folders (Box 436)
      - Miscellaneous chapters (Box 436)
      - Front and back matter (Box 436)
      - Dutton agreement (Box 436)
      - Miscellaneous notes (Box 436)
    - Baby and Child Care Ninth Edition (2012), with Robert Needlman
      - Edited draft, pp. i-369, 2 folders (Box 436)
      - Edited draft, pp. 370-995, index, 5 folders (Box 437)
      - Proofs, pp. i-379, including cover; 2 folders (Box 437)
      - Proofs, pp. 380-1086, 2 folders (Box 438)
      - Proofs, edited pages (Box 438)
    - Baby and Child Care, unidentified editions, material from various editions of the book
      - Consultant comments, 3 folders (Box 438)
      - Draft A, 2 folders (Box 438)
      - Revisions, 3 folders (Box 439)
      - Miscellaneous, list of possible editors, with comments; list of foreign editions; press release (Box 439)
    - Baby and Child Care Medical Record Book, includes notes, mockup of booklet (Box 439)
    - A Baby's First Year, preface (Box 439)
    - A Better World for Our Children, 1958
      - Contract (Box 439)
      - Correspondence, general, 1992-1994; undated; 4 folders (Box 439)
      - Correspondence, Alexia Dorszynski (Box 439)
      - Editing log (Box 439)
      - Minor release forms (Box 439)
      - Photo shoot (Box 439)
      - Drafts, 1992 (Box 439)
      - Drafts, 1992; 7 folders (Box 440)
      - Drafts, 1993; 7 folders (Box 441)
      - Drafts, 1993-1994; 8 folders (Box 442)
      - Drafts, 1993-1994; 4 folders (Box 443)
      - Drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box 443)
      - Drafts, undated; 4 folders (Box 444)
      - Omitted chapters (Box 444)
      - Proofs, including cover; 3 folders (Box 444)
      - Proofs, 3 folders (Box 445)
      - Revisions, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 445)
      - Typescript manuscript with revisions, sections I-VI, 2 foldes (Box 445)
      - Typescript manuscript with revisions, section VII to end (Box 446)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 446)
    - Caring for your Disabled Child, 2 folders (Box 446)
    - Decent and Indecent
      - Acknowledgements (Box 446)
      - Dedication (Box 446)
      - Draft A, 2 folders (Box 446)
      - Drafts B-G, 6 folders (Box 447)
      - Drafts H-L, 5 folders (Box 448)
      - Draft, mimeograph copy, 2 folders (Box 448)
      - Draft, mimeograph copy (Box 449)
      - Galleys, 3 folders (Box 449)
      - Introduction (Box 449)
      - Not used (Box 449)
      - Not used (Box 450)
      - Notes (Box 450)
      - Parts I and II, 5 folders (Box 450)
      - Parts III through VI, 4 folders (Box 451)
      - Preview (Box 451)
      - Proofs, advance, bound volume (Box 451)
      - Publicity (Box 451)
      - Published edition, Fawcett Crest paperback; 2 copies (Box 451)
      - "A Reactionary View of Obscenity and Brutality", handwritten draft(s) (Box 451)
      - Revisions (Box 451)
      - Revisions, 4 folders (Box 452)
      - Revisions, 5 folders (Box 453)
      - Revisions, 3 folders (Box 454)
      - Students' comments, 2 folders (Box 454)
      - Students' comments, 4 folders (Box 455)
      - Students' comments (Box 456)
      - Typescript, pp. 1-347, 2 folders (Box 456)
      - Typescript, pp. 1-347 (incomplete), 2 folders (Box 456)
      - Typescript, pp. 1-347, 2 folders (Box 457)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 457)
    - Dr Spock on Parenting
      - Correspondence (Box 457)
      - Copy-edited manuscript, 5 folders (Box 457)
      - Draft, undated; 4 folders (Box 458)
      - Draft, partial, 24 Mar 1988 (Box 458)
      - Drafts, ch. 1-4, 4 folders (Box 458)
      - Drafts, ch. 5-10, miscellaneous, 8 folders (Box 459)
      - "First draft, second edit", 6 folders (Box 459)
      - "First draft, second edit" [cont.] (Box 460)
      - "Original manuscript" pp. 1-270, 3 folders (Box 460)
      - "Original manuscript" pp. 271-444, 3 folders (Box 461)
      - Outline (Box 461)
      - Proofs, cover (Box 461)
      - Proofs, front matter and back matter (Box 461)
      - Source material, 7 folders (Box 461)
      - Source material (Box 462)
      - "To be considered" (Box 462)
    - Dr. Spock Talks With Mothers, outline, cover proofs, front matter proofs, miscellaneous (Box 462)
    - Dr. Spock on Vietnam
      - Correspondence (Box 462)
      - Drafts (Box 462)
    - Dr. Spock's The First Two Years, collection of essays originally written for Parenting, edited by Martin Stein
      - Cover proof (Box 462)
      - Source material, copies of original articles, with edits; 2 folders (Box 462)
      - Typescript with corrections (Box 462)
    - Dr. Spock's The School Years, collection of essays originally written for Parenting, edited by Martin Stein
      - Cover proof (Box 463)
      - Source material, copies of original articles, with edits; 3 folders (Box 463)
      - Typescript with corrections, 2 folders (Box 463)
    - Feeding Your Baby and Child, disbound printed pages, glued to backing sheets (Box 463)
    - Foreword to unidentified book by Gale Slap (Box 463)
    - "How to Talk to Your Children About Love and Sex and AIDS", for New York State Department of Health; typescript and handwritten notes, drafts (Box 463)
    - Parents' Almanac chapter, "What's Permissive?", typescript and handwritten notes, drafts (Box 463)
    - Peek-A-Boo: Picture Story of a Baby [unpublished] (Box 464)
    - Problems of Parents, Preface (Box 464)
    - Raising Children in a Difficult Time
      - Camera copy, 2-page spread (Box 464)
      - Camera copy, single sheets, 2 folders (Box 464)
      - Correspondence, reviews, 1973-1975; undated (Box 464)
      - Front matter, back matter (Box 464)
      - Galleys, Master Set 1st Pass (Box 464)
      - Galleys, Master Set Confirmation (2 copies), 2 folders (Box 464)
      - Introduction [?] (Box 465)
      - Manuscript with edits, 3 folders (Box 465)
      - Manuscript with edits, photocopy, 3 folders (Box 465)
      - Notes, ch. 1-8 (Box 465)
      - Notes, ch. 10-11 (Box 466)
      - Photographs, contact sheets only (Box 466)
      - Miscellaneous, includes review in New York Times Book Review; notes for possible revision (Box 466)
    - Spock on Spock
      - Correspondence, 1936; 1945-1948,; 1988-1990,; undated; material pre-1980 is all photocopies of correspondence with publisher; 9 folders (Box 466)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 467)
      - "Ben's corrections", 2 sets; 6 folders (Box 467)
      - "Dead pages", 2 folders (Box 467)
      - "Doug's outtakes" (Box 468)
      - Draft, incomplete, 3 folders (Box 468)
      - Draft, Mar-May 1989 (Box 468)
      - Draft, copy 1, April 1989 (Box 468)
      - Draft, copy 2, April 1989 (Box 469)
      - Draft, incomplete, May 1989; 2 folders (Box 469)
      - Drafts of introduction, acknowledgements, 2 folders (Box 469)
      - Drafts, chapter 1, 2 folders (Box 469)
      - Drafts, World War II section (Box 469)
      - Drafts, index (Box 469)
      - Drafts, miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 470)
      - Outline, multiple drafts (Box 470)
      - "Peter stories" (Box 470)
      - Galleys [set A], 3 folders (Box 471)
      - Galleys [set B], 2 folders (Box 471)
      - Galleys [set C], 2 folders (Box 471)
      - Master galleys, 2 folders (Box 471)
      - Galleys, partial, 2 folders (Box 472)
      - Galleys, miscellaneous (Box 472)
      - Photos and captions, photocopies only, no original prints; 4 folders (Box 473)
      - Proofs [?], incomplete (Box 473)
      - Publicity (Box 473)
      - Tape transcripts, 1, tape 1 (Box 473)
      - Tape transcripts, 2-16, tapes 2-16; 10 folders (Box 474)
      - Tape transcripts, 17-34, tapes 17-34; 9 folders (Box 475)
      - Tape transcripts, 35-40, tables 35-40; 2 folders (Box 476)
      - Tape transcripts, edited and reordered, essentially an early draft of the book; raw transcripts cut and pasted in preferred order, extensively annotated by Mary Morgan; 6 folders (Box 476)
      - Tape transcripts, unidentified (Box 476)
      - Tape transcripts, Mary Morgan's lists, lists, descriptions, notes (Box 477)
      - Tape transcripts, duplicate set, lists, descriptions, notes (Box 551)
      - Typescript with edits, 5 folders (Box 477)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 477)
    - A Teenager's Guide to Life and Love
      - Correspondence (Box 478)
      - Drafts, drafts were not labeled or organized, so have simply been transferred into new folders in the groupings and order they originally had; 8 folders (Box 478)
      - Drafts, 7 folders (Box 479)
      - Drafts, 4 folders (Box 480)
      - Publicity (Box 480)
      - Setting copy, 2 folders (Box 480)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 480)
  - Speeches and lectures
    - Active pursuit of peace (subject), 1968 (Box 481)
    - Afghanistan, Before and After, undated (Box 481)
    - Arms control (subject), 1965 (Box 481)
    - Aspects of Latency, 1959; Western Reserve University Clinical Science (Box 481)
    - Bringing Up a More Peaceful Generation, 1965 (Box 481)
    - Casualties in America of the War in Vietnam, 1966 (Box 481)
    - "Cold War Trauma or Challenge?", 1964; Child Study Association of America (Box 481)
    - Costs of the war in Vietnam (subject), 1966 (Box 481)
    - Dentists and child patients (subject), 1954 (Box 481)
    - Depression (subject), 1989 (Box 481)
    - Endorsement of John F. Kennedy for President, 1960 (Box 481)
    - Equal rights for women (subject) (Box 481)
    - Greetings from the American Peace Movement (Box 481)
    - Handicapped children (subject) (Box 481)
    - Infant Feeding From Various Perspectives, 1959; Western Reserve University (Box 481)
    - Mental Health for Children, 1951; University of Pittsburgh (Box 481)
    - The Middle Aged Child, 1946 (Box 481)
    - The Multi-Discipline Approach in Professional Education, University of Pittsburgh (Box 481)
    - Multilateral force (subject) (Box 481)
    - Multiple Tensions in Our Society, 1986 (Box 481)
    - My Health Story, 1993 (Box 481)
    - Needs of parents (subject), 1957; Midwestern Associationfor Nursery Education (Box 481)
    - On Raising Our Children in a Cold War Age (Box 481)
    - Opinions on Medical Education (Box 481)
    - Peace and Justice for All People", 1967; Chicago Rally (Box 481)
    - A Pediatric View of How Undergraduate Education Might Better Meet the Community's Needs, Rochester (MN) Child Health Institute (Box 481)
    - Psychological problems in medical practice with children (subject), 1954 (Box 481)
    - Radioactive fallout (subject), 1962 (Box 481)
    - Raising Children in the Television Era (Children and TV), 1985 (Box 481)
    - Raising Our Children in an Age of Violence, 1967 (Box 482)
    - Remarks at Spring Mobilization, 1967 (Box 482)
    - The School Age Child, 1962; Notre Dame Child Guidance Clinic Glasgow (Box 482)
    - Separating Prevention from Therapy in Psychiatry, 1954 (Box 482)
    - Sociability (subject) (Box 482)
    - Statement of Benjamin Spock, 1967; Washington, DC (Box 482)
    - Talks With Parents, 1966; Foster Home Recruiting Center Cleveland, OH (Box 482)
    - Teaching the Broader Aspects of Pediatrics, 1948 (Box 482)
    - Vietnam (subject), 1965; March on Washington (Box 482)
    - What Are the Real Dangers of the Cold War? (Box 482)
    - What Future for Our Children? (Box 482)
    - Why Do We Betray Peace and Justice?, 1965 (Box 482)
    - Why We Are in Trouble in Vietnam, 1965 (Box 482)
    - The Wider Dimensions of Mental Health, 1980; Margaret Mead Memorial Lecture; includes printed version (Box 482)
    - Notes and fragments, 4 folders (Box 482)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Comments on books (Box 483)
    - Cornell University Medical College Alumni Association, 1982; Spock's recollections (Box 483)
    - Dr. Spock speaks to children about scheduling (school interviews), includes draft of article "The Over-Scheduled Child" (Box 483)
    - Four Awakenings, no author is given; probably not by Spock (Box 483)
    - Interview of Spock, by Ted Gittinger, 1982 (Box 483)
    - Killing Our Own, Introduction (Box 483)
    - Love and the Other Impulses, handwritten draft(s) (Box 483)
    - My Harvard, My Yale / The Mother's Boy and the New Coach, includes correspondence with editor Diana DuBois (Box 483)
    - My wishes for old age and death (Box 483)
    - Optimal Health for All of Us, O'Donnell [earlier title: Health Promotion: The Next Stage in the Evolution of Medicine], 1983-1985; Spock was to be Senior Editor on the project; includes correspondence with Michael O'Donnell of the San Jose Health Center, Lescher & Lescher, others (Box 483)
    - Spirituality (poem) (Box 483)
    - "Voices of Concern" statement, 1977; on teenage health (Box 483)
    - Your Premature Baby, Robin Henig, Foreword (Box 483)
    - War Toys campaign statement, 1987 (Box 483)
    - Unidentified notes and fragments, 2 folders (Box 483)
    - Unidentified notes and fragments, 2 folders (Box 484)
  - By Mary Morgan
    - Backlash of the women's movement in the 1980s, 1986; UCLA (Box 484)
    - The Block, on writer's block (Box 484)
    - Call me Mary Morgan, not Mrs. Spock, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Campobello, 1982 (Box 484)
    - Christianity, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Defense vs. freedom, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Euromissiles, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Freedom vs. equal rights, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Hello 40, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Invasion of Grenada, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Korean airliner, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Marooned on Ginger Lagoon, 1983 (Box 484)
    - Mary Morgan at Age 40, undated (Box 484)
    - Memories of Ben (Box 484)
    - Poetry (Box 485)
    - Raising children in a most difficult (or nuclear) age (Box 485)
    - "Sailing with Ben" sample chapter, proposed book (Box 485)
    - SANE Peace Award banquet speech, 1982 (Box 485)
    - Step-parent notes, undated (Box 485)
    - Stories Ben Told Me, 2000; Yale Club (Box 485)
    - Stresses on working women, undated; notes only (Box 485)
    - A summer cruise on Turtle, 1983 (Box 485)
    - What will the year 2000 hold for us?, 1986; Mid-America Congress on Aging (Box 485)
    - Woman prisoner, undated (Box 485)
    - WomanSpace talk, Cleveland, 1987 (Box 485)
  - By others
    - Bindman, Stephen / Love without illusions, 1984; bound typescript (Box 554)
    - Cable, Mary / The little darlings, 1975; bound galleys, jacket, letter from Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 555)
    - Lampell, Millard / Day of judgement, 1974; bound screenplay, Palomar Pictures (Box 555)
    - Lipschutz, Abbie / The last butterfly, 1980; bound typescript; includes letter from author to Mary Morgan, and text of her remarks at ACLU meeting (Box 555)
    - Pryor, Karen / Nursing your baby, 1973; galleys (Box 555)
    - Rynders, Henry / The celestial fix on land and sea, 1973; bound typescript, signed and inscribed to Spock (Box 555)